<INC-CONTENTS for="http://www.xcontest.org" created="2007-09-07 13:26:42">
<CONTENT for="/india/" label="XC India 2015">
<div>
  <a href="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/12697061/8005715/c192303e-0baa-11e5-96f2-39c8ce752586.gif" target="_blank"><img src="https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/12697061/8005715/c192303e-0baa-11e5-96f2-39c8ce752586.gif" alt="Paragliders - GIFMANIA" class="art-img-thumb-right" style="width: 198px; height: 240px; float: right; margin-left:10px" height="240" width="198"/></a>
<p>
Dear Pilot,
</p>
<p>
Welcome to the Home Page of <strong>XC India 2015</strong>, an online XC contest. The XContest India [XC INDIA] is a competition in which all pilots regardless of flight experience and age are given the opportunity to evaluate their flights and to compare them with others.The idea is to connect all pilots (serious cross country pilots or recreational pilots) according to their time and financial possibilities.It is the pleasure of flying that connects all the participants.
If you’d like to participate in this contest, you have to claim your flights on this site <a href="http://www.xcontest.org/india/" style="text-decoration: none;"> <span style="color: rgb(17,85,204);text-decoration: underline;">XContest.org/india/</span> </a>.
<table border="0" class="table-invisible" style="margin-top: 15px; border: 1px solid rgb(218, 218, 218);"><tbody><tr>
<td><p><strong>XC INDIA </strong>Contest on <strong>Facebook</strong>:</p></td>
<td style="padding-top: 5px;"><iframe frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true" style="border: medium none; overflow: hidden; width: 400px; height: 35px;" scrolling="no" src="//www.facebook.com/plugins/like.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2indianxc&amp;width=400&amp;layout=standard&amp;action=like&amp;show_faces=false&amp;share=false&amp;height=35"></iframe></td></tr></tbody></table>

<!--
 ========================================================================================================= 
-->
<h2 style="line-height: 140%;border-bottom : 1px dashed; font-size: 130%"><strong>NEWS</strong></h2>
<!--
 ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ 
-->
<h3><em><strong>03.06.2015 - Club 100K+</strong></em></h3>
<p>The 100k club scoring has simplified rules: the score counts of 100k+ flights regardless of the takeoff/site used</p>
<!--
 ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ 
-->
<h3><em><strong>02.06.2015 - Game On</strong></em></h3>
<p>The XC India 2015 is online. You can now submit all flights since 1st Jan 2015. Currently there is no deadline to submit flights until the end of competition season(31st Dec 2015) but this may change for next season.</p>
<!--
 ========================================================================================================= 
-->
<h2 style="line-height: 140%;border-bottom : 1px dashed; font-size: 130%"><strong>Basic page structure:</strong></h2> 
<p><em>Left menu</em>: Contains references to pages with information about flights, pilots and ranking in particular classes. Here you can also find rules and FAQ’s.<br /><em>Right menu:</em> ‘For Pilots’ contains references to pages which the pilot can use for registration, flight claims, pilot profile management, etc.</p>
<!--
 ========================================================================================================= 
-->
<h2 style="line-height: 140%;border-bottom : 1px dashed; font-size: 130%"><strong>Administrator contact:</strong></h2> 
<p>If you have any questions about the XC India competition, or any suggestions for improvements or alterations regarding the competition or content on the site, please contact:<br /><strong>Alok Mihani</strong>: <u><a href="mailto:alokmihani@gmail.com">alokmihani@gmail.com</a></u></p> <p>ph. +91-9980915533</p>
</p>
</div>
</CONTENT>
<CONTENT for="/india/ranking-teams/">
<div>
For the class "PG team" – Maximum allowed members in the team are 3. Best three flights of each individual member of the team will be used for scoring. It will be a combined score of all the team members.
</div>
</CONTENT>
<CONTENT for="/india/ranking-club-100plus/">
<div>
This category includes all pilots who have logged at least 1 flight over 100 km. Ranking is given by the number of such flights. In the case of equal number of flights over 100k the second aspect for ranking is the longest flight of pilot
</div>
</CONTENT>
<CONTENT for="/india/ranking-pg-open/">
<div>
  Open category lists all ranked pilots with minimum 1 flight. The score is given by 6 best flights (any kind of glider). Please note that the final score will calculate only 2 best flights from a site. This means a pilot must attempt to fly atleast 3 sites to maximize the score.  Two site must be  atleast 50kms apart from each other. 
</div>
</CONTENT>
<CONTENT for="/india/ranking-sport/">
<div>
  All pilots with flights on max. sport paraglider <strong>(max.EN C/LTF C)</strong>. The score is given by 6 best flights. Please note that the final score will calculate only 2 best flights from a site. This means a pilot must attempt to fly atleast 3 sites to maximize the score.  Two site must be  atleast 50kms apart from each other.
</div>
</CONTENT>
<CONTENT for="/india/ranking-standard/">
<div>
  All pilots with flights on max. sport paraglider <strong> (max. DHV 1-2, AFNOR/SHV Standard, CEN B)</strong>. The score is given by 6 best flights. Please note that the final score will calculate only 2 best flights from a site. This means a pilot must attempt to fly atleast 3 sites to maximize the score.  Two site must be  atleast 50kms apart from each other.
</div>
</CONTENT>
<CONTENT for="/india/ranking-women/">
<div>
  All women with minimum 1 flight. The score is given by 6 best flights (any kind of glider). Please note that the final score will calculate only 2 best flights from a site. This means a pilot must attempt to fly atleast 3 sites to maximize the score.  Two site must be  atleast 50kms apart from each other.
</div>
</CONTENT>
<CONTENT for="/india/rules/">
<div>
  <!--
 ========================================================================================================= 
-->
  <h2 style="line-height: 140%; padding: 5px;  background-color: #EBF5F6;  border-top: 1px solid #BDD4DD;  border-bottom: 1px dashed #BDD4DD;  font-size: 120%;  letter-spacing: 0.1em"><strong>XC India 2015 Competition Rules</strong></h2>
  <p><h3 style="line-height: 140%; padding: 2px 5px 1px 5px;font-size: 100%; font-style: italic; border-top: 1px solid #BDD4DD; border-bottom: 1px dashed #BDD4DD; background-image: url(https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/12697061/8005954/f6b24b4e-0bac-11e5-8e1b-1c011f388f8a.JPG);  background-position: 0 0px;  background-repeat: repeat-x">
      <strong>1. General Information</strong> 
    </h3>
    </p>
    <p><strong> 1.1 Summary </strong></p>

    <p>
      The XContest India [XC INDIA] is a competition in which all pilots regardless of flight experience and age are given the opportunity to evaluate their flights and to compare them with others.The idea is to connect all pilots (serious cross country pilots or recreational pilots) according to their time and financial possibilities.It is the pleasure of flying that connects all the participants.
    </p>
    <p><strong>
      1.2 Promoters and Organizers
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      This is a <strong> For the Pilots By the Pilots</strong> initiative. Some enthusiastic pilots have come together to organize this contest in India with <a href="http://www.xcontest.org/" style="text-decoration: none;"> <span style="color: rgb(47,88,123);text-decoration: underline;">XContest.org</span> </a>
    </p>
    <p><strong>
      1.3 Competitors
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      Any pilot who considers India their home can compete in this contest. Pilot can be an Indian citizen pilot or any foreigner who has been residing in India for more than a year.  
    </p>
    <p><strong>
      1.4 Entry Fees :
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      No entry fee is required.
    </p>
   <p><strong>
      1.5 Eligibility 
     </strong></p>
    <p>
      Currently we have very no eligibility criteria, However we do recommend that
    </p>
    <ol>
      <li style="text-decoration: none;">
        <p>
          Pilot must have gone through necessary training to be able to do Cross Country Flying
        </p>
      </li>
      <li style="text-decoration: none;">
        <p>
          Pilot must possess necessary insurance which covers fatalities due to paragliding (including third party liabilities)
        </p>
      </li>
    </ol>
      <!--
 ========================================================================================================= 
-->
      <p><h3 style="line-height: 140%; padding: 2px 5px 1px 5px;font-size: 100%; font-style: italic; border-top: 1px solid #BDD4DD; border-bottom: 1px dashed #BDD4DD; background-image: url(https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/12697061/8005954/f6b24b4e-0bac-11e5-8e1b-1c011f388f8a.JPG);  background-position: 0 0px;  background-repeat: repeat-x">
      <strong>2. General Rules </strong>
      </h3>
      </p>
    <p>
      The following listed deviations apply to the XContest India [XC India] in 2015 in addition to the currently valid regulations of the World XContest.
    </p>
    <p><strong>
      2.1 Flying Rules
    </strong></p>
    <p>
       If a pilot is found by the organizer or national administrator/s to have submitted a flight which infringes Indian Air laws, the flight will be removed from the scoring.
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li style="text-decoration: none;">
        <p>
          Flights have to be done in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visual_flight_rules" style="text-decoration: none;"> <span style="color: rgb(17,85,204);text-decoration: underline;"> VFR</span></a> and is totally in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Visual_meteorological_conditions" style="text-decoration: none;"> <span style="color: rgb(17,85,204);text-decoration: underline;"> VMC</span></a>. It means no cloud flying and no night flying. In case of complaint Meteorological cloudbase will be used for that day to check flight log and data from other pilots flight for same day can be used. Some margin will be given from met cloudbase depending on situation.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li style="text-decoration: none;">
        <p>
          Flights have to be unassisted. Guided flights will not be counted.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li style="text-decoration: none;">
        <p>
          Its pilot's responsibility to make himself aware of airspace restriction in his area and to avoid any restricted airspace.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li style="text-decoration: none;">
        <p>
          Only certified paragliders allowed.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li style="text-decoration: none;">
        <p>
          Any liability or personal loss arising out of flights for this online competition is pilots own responsibility.
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <p><strong>
      2.2 Competition Duration
    </strong></p>
    <ul>
    <li style="text-decoration: none;">  
    <p>
      The XContest India [XC India] starts at 1st Jan . 2015
    </p>
    </li>
    <li style="text-decoration: none;">
    <p>
      Competition end on 31st Dec 2015. Last day of submitting flights for the competition duration is 9th January 2016
    </p>
    </li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Note: The 2016 season begins on 1st Jan 2016
    </p>
    <p><strong> 
      2.3 Area of Contest :
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      <strong>Worldwide</strong> : Flying site can be anywhere in the world.
    </p>
    <p><strong>
      2.4 Registration
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      To participate in the XContest India [XC India] each participant must register on <a href="http://www.xcontest.org/india" style="text-decoration: none;"> <span style="color: rgb(17,85,204);text-decoration: underline;">http://www.xcontest.org/india</span> </a>. With its subscriber registration, the participant accepts the rules of the World XContest and the additions / deviations of XContest India.
    </p>
    <p><strong> 
      2.5 Launch Methods
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      Foot-launch, winch-launch
    </p>
    <!--
      ========================================================================================================= 
    -->
          <p><h3 style="line-height: 140%; padding: 2px 5px 1px 5px;font-size: 100%; font-style: italic; border-top: 1px solid #BDD4DD; border-bottom: 1px dashed #BDD4DD; background-image: url(https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/12697061/8005954/f6b24b4e-0bac-11e5-8e1b-1c011f388f8a.JPG);  background-position: 0 0px;  background-repeat: repeat-x">
      <strong>3. Flight Documentation </strong>
    </h3>
    </p>
    <p>
      The XContest India [XC India] allows pilots to fly cross country without having to declare a task before take off. Documenting a flight may only be done through the use of an appropriate instrument:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li style="text-decoration: none;">
    <p>
      Standalone GPS
    </p>
    </li>
    <li style="text-decoration: none;">
      <p>
      GPS with variometer and barograph
    </p>
    </li>
    <li style="text-decoration: none;">
    <p>
      GPS integrated flying instruments
    </p>
    </li>
    <li style="text-decoration: none;">
    <p>
      Data Logger
    </p>
    </li>
    <li style="text-decoration: none;">
    <p>
      Appropriate Smartphones with necessary applications
    </p>
    </li>
    <p>
      All flights must be recorded in 3d.
    </p>
    <p>
      Further information on compulsory features necessary for instruments and software can be found in section 8's "Technical specifications” of these Rules.
    </p>
    </ul>
    <p><strong>
      3.1 IGC flight data
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      Every pilot must keep a personal backup of all his / her tracklog files uploaded to the XContest server until 1 calendar month after the flight has been submitted. Once a pilot has uploaded an IGC tracklog file to the XContest server it becomes the public property
    </p>
    <p><strong> 
      3.2 Deadline of flight submission
     </strong></p>
    <p>
      Currently there is no deadline for 2015 season as long as a pilot is submitting flight during the competition duration that is 1st of Jan to 31st Dec.
    </p>
    <p>
      These deadlines may change for next season.
    </p>
    <p>
      Please note if you wish your flight to be considered for the World XContest then you will have to follow their deadlines. The deadline for uploading a flight for World XContest is 14 days after day of the flight. Flights which are claimed after the deadline will be rejected for World XContest
    </p>
<!--
 ========================================================================================================= 
-->
          <p><h3 style="line-height: 140%; padding: 2px 5px 1px 5px;font-size: 100%; font-style: italic; border-top: 1px solid #BDD4DD; border-bottom: 1px dashed #BDD4DD; background-image: url(https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/12697061/8005954/f6b24b4e-0bac-11e5-8e1b-1c011f388f8a.JPG);  background-position: 0 0px;  background-repeat: repeat-x">
      <strong>4. Classification </strong>
    </h3>
    </p>
    <p><strong>
      4.1 Evaluation of Tracks
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      After landing, the recorded tracklog should be examined to determine the scoring distance flown. Here the start point, up to 3 turnpoints and the finish point are to be positioned on the tracklog to provide the greatest possible distance. A flight may be scored as a triangle, when the distance between start point and finish point is less than 20% of the entire distance as given by the 3 turnpoints. The scoring distance will then be given by the turnpoint distance, minus the gap (finish to start) distance.
    </p>
    <p><strong> 
      4.2 Track Values
    </strong></p>
    <ul>
      <li style="text-decoration: none;">
        <p>
          Free flight
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Free distance which not conform the triangle track specification. 1 km = 1.00 point
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li style="text-decoration: none;">
        <p>
          Flat triangle
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Triangle which not conform FAI triangle specification. 1 km = 1.20 points
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li style="text-decoration: none;">
        <p>
          FAI triangle
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Triangle conform to the FAI definition (the shortest leg of the triangle must be at least 28% of the total triangle).1 km = 1.40 points
    </p>
    <p>
      The scoring rule which gives the most points will always be used. All scoring results will be rounded to 2 decimal places. For valuation of each flight will be chosen from a such tracks, whose distance exceed the minimum distance.
    </p>
    <p><strong> 
      4.3 Evaluating Flight Tracklog
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      After landing, the recorded tracklog should be transferred to a computer to the valid IGC file format. Once this has occurred, the IGC file should be uploaded to the XContest server to be entered in the scoring.
    </p>
    <!--
 ========================================================================================================= 
-->
          <p><h3 style="line-height: 140%; padding: 2px 5px 1px 5px;font-size: 100%; font-style: italic; border-top: 1px solid #BDD4DD; border-bottom: 1px dashed #BDD4DD; background-image: url(https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/12697061/8005954/f6b24b4e-0bac-11e5-8e1b-1c011f388f8a.JPG);  background-position: 0 0px;  background-repeat: repeat-x">
            <strong>5. Competition Class, Provisional and Final results</strong>
    </h3>
    </p>
    <p><strong> 
      5.1 No of flights that count for final score
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      ">A pilot may register as many flights as he or she may wish; but the final score will calculate only 2 best flights from a site (50 km radius). Maximum 6 flights will be taken for the final score. This means a pilot must attempt to fly atleast 3 sites ( one site is atleast 50kms apart from other )to maximize the score.
    </p>
    <p><strong> 
      5.2 Classes
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      <strong> PG open</strong> score – best 6 flights of pilot on any paraglider (FAI-3)
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>PG sport [EN A/B/C]</strong> score - best 6 flights of pilot on paraglider max. EN C
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>PG standard [EN A/B]</strong> score– best 6 flights of pilot on paraglider max. EN B
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>PG TEAM</strong> - Best three flights of each individual member of the team will be used for scoring. It will be a combined score of all the team members. Maximum no pf team members = 3
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong> 100K + club</strong> - The category includes all pilots who have logged at least 1 flight over 100 km. Ranking is given by the number of such flights. In the case of equal number of flights over 100k the second aspect for ranking is the longest flight of pilot.
    </p>
    <p><strong>
      5.3 Multiple ratings
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      On the basis of submitted Flights automatically the respective rating classes are added. Flights with low classified paragliders are also counted in the higher rating classes. (Eg a flight with an EN-B screen is also seen in the  "PG Sport" and "PG Open".) 
    </p>
    <p><strong> 
      5.4 Team Classification
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      For the class "PG team" – Maximum allowed members in the team are 3. Best three flights of each individual member of the team will be used for scoring. It will be a combined score of all the team members
    </p>
    <p><strong> 
      5.5 Provisional Results
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      Provisional results will be constantly updated and may be viewed on <a href="http://www.xcontest.org/india" style="text-decoration: none;"> <span style="color: rgb(17,85,204);text-decoration: underline;">http://www.xcontest.org/india</span> </a>
    </p>
    <p><strong> 
      5.6 Final Results
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      Final results are valid once the protest deadline has been reached. Final results may also be viewed under <a href="http://www.xcontest.org/india" style="text-decoration: none;"> <span style="color: rgb(17,85,204);text-decoration: underline;">http://www.xcontest.org/india</span> </a>
    </p>
    <p><strong>
      5.7 Prizes
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      This section will be updated later :-)
    </p>
    <!--
 ========================================================================================================= 
-->
          <p><h3 style="line-height: 140%; padding: 2px 5px 1px 5px;font-size: 100%; font-style: italic; border-top: 1px solid #BDD4DD; border-bottom: 1px dashed #BDD4DD; background-image: url(https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/12697061/8005954/f6b24b4e-0bac-11e5-8e1b-1c011f388f8a.JPG);  background-position: 0 0px;  background-repeat: repeat-x">
            <strong>6. Liability and Disqualification </strong>
    </h3>
    </p>
    <p><strong>
      6.1 Liability
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      The organisers accept no liability for damages to competitors or third parties.
    </p>
    <p><strong>
      6.2 Disqualification
    </strong></p>
    <p>
      Competitors who wilfully make false flight claims or fail to comply with these regulations in order to benefit themselves in the scoring, or who give good cause for belief that this is so, can be disqualified from the competition. 
      Kindly pay attention while entering the class of glider
    </p>
    <!--
 ========================================================================================================= 
-->
      <p><h3 style="line-height: 140%; padding: 2px 5px 1px 5px;font-size: 100%; font-style: italic; border-top: 1px solid #BDD4DD; border-bottom: 1px dashed #BDD4DD; background-image: url(https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/12697061/8005954/f6b24b4e-0bac-11e5-8e1b-1c011f388f8a.JPG);  background-position: 0 0px;  background-repeat: repeat-x">
<strong>7. Protests</strong>
    </h3>
</p>
    <p><strong> 
7.1 Protests due to non-acceptance of a flight
     </strong></p>
    <p>
Should a flight not be accepted by the organizer, then every pilot has the right to firstly register a complaint, and thereafter to enter a written protest against the decision.
    </p>
    <p>
Please send your complains to <span style="color: rgb(0,0,0);text-decoration: none;"> <a href="mailto:xcontest.india@gmail.com">xcontest.india@gmail.com</a> </span>
    </p>
    <p>
A protest must arrive no later than one week after the end of season. The jury is responsible for deciding if a protest is valid or not.
    </p>
    <p><strong>
7.2 Jury
    </strong></p>
    <p>
The jury is formed from organizers and makes the final decisions with regard to protests. No further appeals or legal actions are permitted.
    </p>
    <!--
 ========================================================================================================= 
-->
          <p><h3 style="line-height: 140%; padding: 2px 5px 1px 5px;font-size: 100%; font-style: italic; border-top: 1px solid #BDD4DD; border-bottom: 1px dashed #BDD4DD; background-image: url(https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/12697061/8005954/f6b24b4e-0bac-11e5-8e1b-1c011f388f8a.JPG);  background-position: 0 0px;  background-repeat: repeat-x">
<strong>8. Technical Specification</strong>
    </h3>
    </p>
    <p>
Every pilot is responsible for choosing his or her own recording instrument, logger or GPS. The pilot is responsible for recording a continual tracklog, correct transferral, evaluation uploading as an IGC File. Recorded tracklogs may only originate from a single instrument; tracks compiled from recordings from more than one instrument will not be accepted.
    </p>
    <p>
      Should a logger split a continual flight into more than one tracklog, then the pilot should contact the manufacturer to rectify this problem. Manufacturers which certify their instruments as GNSS approved loggers(FR, flight recorder) comply with the FAI regulations.
    </p>
    <p><strong> 
      8.1 GPS hardware recommendations
    </strong></p>
    <p>
The organizer makes no special recommendations regarding GPS hardware. Flight documentation performed via GPS is fully equivalent to that performed with a GNSS-logger. The compatibility of a particular piece of GPS hardware is largely dependant on the supporting s oftware available for it.
    </p>
    <p><strong>
8.2 Recording interval
    </strong></p>
    <p>
A continuously recorded tracklog must have at least one position recording per minute – i.e. the maximum recording inter v al is 60 seconds. It is recommended that the tracklog recording interval be set between 5 and 15 seconds to reduce the chance of a 60 second interval with no position recordings occurring. Should a pilot intentionally switch off the GPS during a flight, this invalidates the tracklog.
    </p>
    <p><strong>
8.3 GPS failure
    </strong></p>
    <p>
GPS failures may result in one or more breaks in the tracklog longer than 60 seconds. One or two seperate GPS failures less than 15 minutes lon g within a tracklog will be accepted.
    </p>
    <p>
      Flights with GPS failures of longer than 15 minutes or more then two separate GPS failures will not be allowed for the registering and scoring.
    </p>
  </div>
</CONTENT>
</INC-CONTENTS>
