<INC-CONTENTS for="http://www.xcontest.org" created="2007-09-07 13:26:42">
<CONTENT for="/india/" label="XC India 2015">
<div>
<p>
Dear Pilot,
</p>
<p>
Welcome to the Home Page of <strong>XC India 2015</strong>, an online XC contest. The XContest India [XC INDIA] is a competition in which all pilots regardless of flight experience and age are given the opportunity to evaluate their flights and to compare them with others.The idea is to connect all pilots (serious cross country pilots or recreational pilots) according to their time and financial possibilities.It is the pleasure of flying that connects all the participants.
If you’d like to participate in this contest, you have to claim your flights on this site <a href="http://www.xcontest.org/india/" style="text-decoration: none;"> <span style="color: rgb(17,85,204);text-decoration: underline;">XContest.org/india/</span> </a>.
<h2 style="line-height: 140%;border-bottom : 1px dashed; font-size: 130%"><strong>Basic page structure:</strong></h2> 
<p><em>Left menu</em>: Contains references to pages with information about flights, pilots and ranking in particular classes. Here you can also find rules and FAQ’s.<br /><em>Right menu:</em> ‘For Pilots’ contains references to pages which the pilot can use for registration, flight claims, pilot profile management, etc.</p>
<h2><strong>Administrator contact:</strong></h2> <p>If you have any questions about the XC India competition, or any suggestions for improvements or alterations, please contact:<br /><strong>Alok Mihani</strong>: <u><a href="mailto:alokmihani@gmail.com">alokmihani@gmail.com</a></u></p> <p>ph. +91-9980915533</p>
</p>
</div>
</CONTENT>
<CONTENT for="/india/ranking-teams/">
<div>
For the class "PG team" – Maximum allowed members in the team are 3. Best three flights of each individual member of the team will be used for scoring. It will be a combined score of all the team members.
</div>
</CONTENT>
<CONTENT for="/india/ranking-club-100plus/">
<div>
This category includes all pilots who have logged at least 1 flight over 100 km. Ranking is given by the number of such flights. In the case of equal number of flights over 100k the second aspect for ranking is the longest flight of pilot
</div>
</CONTENT>
<CONTENT for="/india/ranking-pg-open/">
<div>
  Open category lists all ranked pilots with minimum 1 flight. The score is given by 6 best flights (any kind of glider). Please note the scoring  the final score will calculate only 2 best flights from a site. This means a pilot must attempt to fly atleast 3 sites to maximize the score.  Two site must be  atleast 50kms apart from each other. 
</div>
</CONTENT>
<CONTENT for="/india/ranking-sport/">
<div>
  All pilots with flights on max. sport paraglider <strong>(max.EN C/LTF C)</strong>. The score is given by 6 best flights. Please note the scoring  the final score will calculate only 2 best flights from a site. This means a pilot must attempt to fly atleast 3 sites to maximize the score.  Two site must be  atleast 50kms apart from each other.
</div>
</CONTENT>
<CONTENT for="/india/ranking-standard/">
<div>
  All pilots with flights on max. sport paraglider <strong> (max. DHV 1-2, AFNOR/SHV Standard, CEN B)</strong>. The score is given by 6 best flights. Please note the scoring  the final score will calculate only 2 best flights from a site. This means a pilot must attempt to fly atleast 3 sites to maximize the score.  Two site must be  atleast 50kms apart from each other.
</div>
</CONTENT>
<CONTENT for="/india/ranking-women/">
<div>
  All women with minimum 1 flight. The score is given by 6 best flights (any kind of glider). Please note the scoring  the final score will calculate only 2 best flights from a site. This means a pilot must attempt to fly atleast 3 sites to maximize the score.  Two site must be  atleast 50kms apart from each other.
</div>
</CONTENT>
<CONTENT for="/india/rules/">
<div>
This content is under preparation. It will be updated once we have all the necessary information.
  </div>
</CONTENT>
</INC-CONTENTS>
